Crystal Yan

Product management and design leader with international experience in emerging markets and a deep commitment to creating design driven company cultures. Experience using behavioral design and artificial intelligence to create meaningful user experiences for B2B and B2C products.

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager & Product Design Manager — FiscalNote, Washington, DC MAR 2016 - PRESENT

- · Head of Design reporting directly to COO/VP of Product, hiring manager responsible for interviewing, hiring, onboarding and training designers
- · Set the vision and roadmap of mobile web and iOS, lead design direction of core user experience (UX) and new features, including EU, South America and Asia product offerings
- · Lead the full-stack design discovery process: conduct qualitative and quantitative UX research with interviews, user testing, and usage metrics analysis; lead creative ideation and wireframing; create interactive high-fidelity prototypes, and test with users to validate hypotheses.
- · Lead delivery sprints with engineering and QA; Develop UI asset and UX pattern library
- · Plan and execute on go-to-market strategy with marketing, sales, and client success teams for new releases that grew average contract value (ACV) from 43.54% from 2015 Q4 to 2016 Q3.

Associate Product Manager & Associate UX Researcher/Designer — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- · Launched company's first iOS app: Produced hi-fidelity prototypes, ran usability testing, started a client beta testing program, iterated designs based on user feedback, and worked with 2 mobile engineers to launch product to a downloadable app in the App Store in four months.
- · Aligned heads of product, sales, client success, and marketing on user personas that guide everything from product strategy to employee onboarding to marketing campaign targeting.
- Designed the first copywriting and UI design style guide for the frontend engineering team.

Business Development Associate — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- Third revenue hire. Interim Head of Marketing for 4 months. Advised VPs with demos to close deals and achieve product-market fit, contributing to company raising \$18 million in funding.
- · Consistently hit but often exceeded monthly quotas; closed \$386,842 in new revenue with shortest sales cycles. Brought on new clients: Uber, Lyft, FireEye, Akin Gump, and Coinbase.
- · Led onboarding sessions for 35+ new hires, trained reps on optimal ways to structure pricing and contract terms in order to maximize ACV and improve cash flow; ACV grew 76.82%.

User Experience Researcher—Innovation Works, Beijing, China

OCT 2012 - DEC 2013

· Led a corporate strategy project in the user experience department for China's premier early-stage investment fund for technology startups

Product Manager - Mobile, Standard Chartered Bank, Shanghai, China AUG 2012 - SEP 2012

- · Led product development & user testing for bilingual iPad app (English/Mandarin) targeting small business owners, increasing customer leads and reducing product support costs
- Analyzed vendor supplier data to identify excess expenses, cut development costs by 27%

Corporate Strategy Summer Analyst, Infosys, Bangalore, India

JUL 2011 - SEP 2011

- Conducted employer branding study, identified HR best practices for 130,000 employees
- · Co-led training for Indian executives on Chinese business culture and doing business in China

SKILLS

Management:

Interviewing, Hiring, Onboarding, Training, Leading **Design Sprints** User Research: Data Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, User Testing Design: Interaction, UI & Visual (Sketch, Adobe CS), Mobile, Prototyping (InVision)

SPEAKING

ULLConf 2016 Killarney, Ireland AIGA DotGovDesign Washington, DC Microsoft Research Asia Beijing, China

EDUCATION

Amherst College BA, Economics, 2014 **Tsinghua University** International Relations Beijing, China, Fall 2012 **International Honors Program Urban Planning &** Anthropology Delhi, Dakar, Buenos Aires, Spring 2013